<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Getting Started with Service Portal on CodeCreative | A ServiceNow Blog</title>
    <link>https://codecreative.io/guides/getting-started-with-service-portal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Getting Started with Service Portal on CodeCreative | A ServiceNow Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 17:55:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://codecreative.io/guides/getting-started-with-service-portal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Service Portal?</title>
      <link>https://codecreative.io/guides/getting-started-with-service-portal/what-is-service-portal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 17:55:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codecreative.io/guides/getting-started-with-service-portal/what-is-service-portal/</guid>
      <description>Service Portal is a powerful framework for building self-service websites and custom web app UIs. Using a hierarchy of table driven components, Service Portal simplifies the process and reduces the code required to build a web interface.
Building Blocks The Service Portal framework uses a combination of well known web libraries and unique framework building blocks to power the UI.
For front-end web developers, a few libraries are in use which are likely familiar:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exercise: Branding the Portal</title>
      <link>https://codecreative.io/guides/getting-started-with-service-portal/branding-the-portal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 17:55:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codecreative.io/guides/getting-started-with-service-portal/branding-the-portal/</guid>
      <description>Objective: To use the Service Portal Branding Editor to modify the branding of a portal.
Exercise GoalModifying the basic branding is a great way to get introduced to Service Portal. It is an easy skill to pick up which requires no code and can be performed by administrators.
In this exercise, we will clone the baseline ITSM portal to create our own portal to modify through the rest of this guide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exercise: Creating a Theme</title>
      <link>https://codecreative.io/guides/getting-started-with-service-portal/creating-a-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 17:55:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codecreative.io/guides/getting-started-with-service-portal/creating-a-theme/</guid>
      <description>Objective: To create a custom theme and apply it to a Service Portal to further modify the portal style.
Exercise GoalCreating a theme takes our styles one step further and brings our portal closer to compliance with a corporate style guide. With just a little SASS and CSS we can take our portal a long way.
In this exercise, we will clone the La Jolla Theme record, modify it&amp;rsquo;s styles, and apply it to the CodeCreative portal we created in the last exercise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exercise: Overriding Styles with CSS Includes</title>
      <link>https://codecreative.io/guides/getting-started-with-service-portal/overriding-styles-with-css-includes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 17:55:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codecreative.io/guides/getting-started-with-service-portal/overriding-styles-with-css-includes/</guid>
      <description>Objective: To further modify the theme and styles, including fonts, using CSS Includes on the Theme record.
Exercise GoalNow that we have a basic theme, let&amp;rsquo;s introduce some new fonts and styles using Theme CSS Includes. CSS Includes are the best place to put CSS styles that should be applied across every page of the portal.
In this exercise, we will create a CSS Include, add it to our CodeCreative Theme record, and update our portals styles to reflect the Exercise Goal pictured above.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exercise: Building a Homepage</title>
      <link>https://codecreative.io/guides/getting-started-with-service-portal/building-a-homepage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 17:55:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codecreative.io/guides/getting-started-with-service-portal/building-a-homepage/</guid>
      <description>Objective: To create a customized homepage for the portal.
Exercise GoalWith the portal level components coming together strong, let&amp;rsquo;s turn our attention to the page level components. Service Portal comes with a built in layout engine that makes assembling pages a breeze.
In this exercise, we will explore cloning and customizing pages in Service Portal by creating a custom homepage.
Exercise Follow the below instructions to complete the exercise:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exercise: Configuring Widgets</title>
      <link>https://codecreative.io/guides/getting-started-with-service-portal/configuring-widgets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 17:55:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codecreative.io/guides/getting-started-with-service-portal/configuring-widgets/</guid>
      <description>Objective: To configure and create simple Widgets in Service Portal
Exercise GoalOne more step to finish up our portal: Widgets. Widgets are the heart and soul of the Service Portal world. All of the content from the header to the footer, the menus, the lists, the forms, all of it is driven by Widgets. Widgets can be as simple or complex as you need.
In this exercise, we will explore the basic foundations of Widgets, Widget Instances, and Instance options which are necessary to begin Widget development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSS and SCSS Processing</title>
      <link>https://codecreative.io/guides/getting-started-with-service-portal/css-and-scss-processing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 17:55:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codecreative.io/guides/getting-started-with-service-portal/css-and-scss-processing/</guid>
      <description>So far we have reviewed many different CSS fields across the Service Portal framework. Since CSS evaluation is highly dependent on it&amp;rsquo;s order, it helps to understand how these different fields get ordered and processed.
Unfortunately, much of the documentation around this can lead to even more confusion. In order to understand the whole picture, we first have to understand that Service Portal does not generate a single blob of CSS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Next Steps</title>
      <link>https://codecreative.io/guides/getting-started-with-service-portal/next-steps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 17:55:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codecreative.io/guides/getting-started-with-service-portal/next-steps/</guid>
      <description>Over the course of this guide, we have covered some basic knowledge and foundational skills for getting started with ServiceNow&amp;rsquo;s Service Portal. At this point you should be able to:
  Create a new Portal
  Style a Portal with a Theme and CSS Includes
  Create and Configure Portal Pages
  Create and Configure Widgets and Widget Instances
  To grow your skills on Service Portal, there are multiple paths that you can pursue:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>