<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Getting Started on ServiceNow on CodeCreative | A ServiceNow Blog</title>
    <link>https://codecreative.io/guides/getting-started-on-servicenow/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Getting Started on ServiceNow on CodeCreative | A ServiceNow Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 20:20:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://codecreative.io/guides/getting-started-on-servicenow/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What is ServiceNow?</title>
      <link>https://codecreative.io/guides/getting-started-on-servicenow/what-is-servicenow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 20:20:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codecreative.io/guides/getting-started-on-servicenow/what-is-servicenow/</guid>
      <description>First and foremost, ServiceNow is a web application you can access through your browser in order to track and automate work. Beyond that basic explanation, ServiceNow is a bit like the software equivalent of the blind men and an elephant parable. What ServiceNow is to you depends largely on which piece of it you get your hands on first. As a company, ServiceNow provides both Platform as a Service (PaaS) and Software as a Service (SaaS) offerings via it&amp;rsquo;s Now Platform in a single tenant architecture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is a ServiceNow Instance?</title>
      <link>https://codecreative.io/guides/getting-started-on-servicenow/what-is-a-servicenow-instance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 20:20:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codecreative.io/guides/getting-started-on-servicenow/what-is-a-servicenow-instance/</guid>
      <description>This is a ServiceNow Instance   As mentioned in the previous section, ServiceNow operates using a single tenant architecture meaning that each customer gets their own copy or multiple copies of ServiceNow in the cloud. These copies are known as ServiceNow instances. Users can access an instance via web browser using each instance&amp;rsquo;s unique URL such as https://companyname.service-now.com.
Each instance can run multiple applications side by side, so a single instance could potentially host an ITSM, HR, CSM, and Custom Apps all at the same base URL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exercise: Get a Personal Developer Instance</title>
      <link>https://codecreative.io/guides/getting-started-on-servicenow/get-a-personal-developer-instance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 20:20:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codecreative.io/guides/getting-started-on-servicenow/get-a-personal-developer-instance/</guid>
      <description>Objective: Obtain and login to ServiceNow Personal Developer Instance
Obtaining ServiceNow Personal Developer Instance (PDI) is your first step to exploring the full potential of the platform and furthering your skills with it. Let&amp;rsquo;s get started!
Exercise Follow the below instructions to complete the exercise:
 In a web browser, navigate to https://developer.servicenow.com/
 Note: Create an account if you do not already have one  Log in to your account</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exercise: Navigating the UI</title>
      <link>https://codecreative.io/guides/getting-started-on-servicenow/navigating-the-ui/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 20:20:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codecreative.io/guides/getting-started-on-servicenow/navigating-the-ui/</guid>
      <description>Objective: Practice basic ServiceNow usage including:
 Navigating ServiceNow
 Viewing records in lists and forms
  Now that we have a Personal Developer Instance, let&amp;rsquo;s learn how to get around and handle the basics of using ServiceNow. These techniques will set the foundation for everything else you can do with ServiceNow.
Exercise Follow the below instructions to complete the exercise:
 Log in to your Personal Developer Instance</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exercise: Filtering Records in the List View</title>
      <link>https://codecreative.io/guides/getting-started-on-servicenow/filtering-records-in-the-list-view/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 20:20:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codecreative.io/guides/getting-started-on-servicenow/filtering-records-in-the-list-view/</guid>
      <description>Objective: Practice filtering records in the list view:
Mastering the list view is one of the more critical skills for new ServiceNow users. In this first List View exercise, we&amp;rsquo;ll focus on different ways of filtering records.
Exercise  In your Personal Developer Instance, navigate to Incident &amp;gt; All
  Using the list header search, find all Incidents containing the Short Description SAP (Learn more about the list header search)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exercise: Creating and Editing Records</title>
      <link>https://codecreative.io/guides/getting-started-on-servicenow/creating-and-editing-records/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 20:20:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codecreative.io/guides/getting-started-on-servicenow/creating-and-editing-records/</guid>
      <description>Objective: Practice creating and editing records in the list and form view:
ServiceNow wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be very useful if you couldn&amp;rsquo;t change the records. Thankfully, there are many different ways to change the data as long as the user has permission. If you are operating in your personal developer instance, you should have admin privileges which will let you edit just about anything.
Exercise  In your Personal Developer Instance, navigate to Incident &amp;gt; Open</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Next Steps</title>
      <link>https://codecreative.io/guides/getting-started-on-servicenow/next-steps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 20:20:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codecreative.io/guides/getting-started-on-servicenow/next-steps/</guid>
      <description>Over the course of this guide, we have covered some basic knowledge and foundational skills for getting started on ServiceNow. At this point you should be able to:
 Obtain a Personal Developer Instance
 Navigate the baseline UI
 Navigate records using the form and list views
 Create and edit records using the form and list views
  With practice and persistence, you can grow these skills to learn the many capabilities that ServiceNow has to offer.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>